github.com/RaghuRam2404

# Raghu Ram

# Software Engineer, Data Science Engineer

Software developer and team lead in Zoho Corporation for more than 5 years of experience. Skilled in team management and software development, looking forward to expand my horizon of knowledge and expecting more challenging problems to work with. Learning AI to improve the knowledge apart from the current works.

# **Experience**

Feb 2014 -

**Member Technical Staff** 

\*

Zoho Corporation Pvt. Ltd.

#### 2018 - \* (Team work)

- · Working on automated API Audit
- Minimizing time on API automation
- Automatic SDK generation
- Automatic Help Doc generation

#### 2016 - Feb 2018 (Team work)

- API v2 release
- SDK on Java/PHP/Ruby
- New API Dashboard

#### 2014 - Feb 2016

- · Enhancements in API
- Zoho Reports Zoho CRM integration
- Zoho Finance Zoho CRM integration

# **Online Certifications**

- Jan 2019 Deep Learning Specialization
- Dec 2018 Machine Learning
- Dec 2018 Statistics with R Specialization

## **Education**

June 2010 - July 2014 B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering (CGPA: 9.03/10)

Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham, Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu

- · Handled website creation for college fest in 2nd year
- · Took classes on PHP and HTML in 4th year
- Done Project on Predicting Age based on the age group and published a paper
- Mocking a website as the windows 7 by web scraping
- College Review project based on J2EE and DB2

June 2008 HSC (Maths & Biology) - 94.92 %

- Apr 2010 S.H.N.V. Matric Hr. Sec. School, Sivakasi, Tamil Nadu

June 2009 SSLC - 95.4 % (District level 3rd position)

- Apr 2008 S.H.N.V. Matric Hr. Sec. School, Sivakasi, Tamil Nadu

### **Hobbies**

- Avid F1 fan
- Play table tennis and cricket
- Travelling
- Occasional book reading

#### **Personal Info**

**Phone** 

+91 9003614468

**Email** 

raghuram2404@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/raghu-ram-2a900444/

#### **Technical Skills**

Java	••••
Struts/Redis	••••
Kafka	•••00
HTML/CSS/JS	•••00
Statistics	•••00
Python/R	•••00
Machine Learning	●0000

# Soft Skills

Leadership

**Task Prioritization** 

Inter team communication

Time Management

Responsibility and Decision making